<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0/rng/docbookxi.rng" type="xml"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">

	<info>
		<title>TestDataCaptureJ Documentation</title>
		<releaseinfo>version 1.0.1</releaseinfo>
		<authorgroup>
			<author>
				<personname>David Wong</personname>
			</author>
		</authorgroup>
		<copyright>
			<year>2010, 2011, 2013</year>
			<holder>David Wong</holder>
		</copyright>
	</info>
	
	<section>
		<title>Overview</title>
		
		<para>The purpose of this tool is to capture test data for unit testing in Java applications. It does this by intercepting method calls
			in the application and logging the contents of objects that you want to use for unit testing. The format of the logged data is in a format
			that can be readily used as test input for tests in JUnit or TestNG, for example.</para>
		<programlisting>// Generated 2011-03-14 17:49:42,390
// org.springframework.samples.jpetstore.domain.Order.initOrder:Parameter1
public org.springframework.samples.jpetstore.domain.Account createParam1Account_org_springframework_samples_jpetstore_domain_Order_initOrder() {

org.springframework.samples.jpetstore.domain.Account account0 = new org.springframework.samples.jpetstore.domain.Account();
account0.setUsername("j2ee");
account0.setPassword(null);
account0.setEmail("yourname@yourdomain.com");
account0.setFirstName("ABC");
account0.setLastName("XYX");
account0.setStatus("OK");
account0.setAddress1("901 San Antonio Road");
account0.setAddress2("MS UCUP02-206");
account0.setCity("Palo Alto");
account0.setState("CA");
account0.setZip("94303");
account0.setCountry("USA");
account0.setPhone("555-555-5555");
account0.setFavouriteCategoryId("DOGS");
account0.setLanguagePreference("english");
account0.setListOption(true);
account0.setBannerOption(true);
account0.setBannerName("&lt;image src=\"../images/banner_dogs.gif\">");

return account0;
}</programlisting>
		<para>The generated logging could then be pasted into a Java class, and the generated methods
			invoked to recreate the object containing the data you want to test. That test object
			could then be used in unit tests for JUnit, TestNG, etc.</para>
		<para>Unlike other test data generation utilities, the primary purpose of this tool is:</para>
		
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>to be used in a Java development environment</para>
			</listitem>
			
			<listitem>
				<para>to capture complex non-persistent data</para>
			</listitem>
			
			<listitem>
				<para>to capture 'real' data for unit testing as opposed to mock data you make up
					yourself</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		
		<para>Note that this tool is meant to used to recreate test objects that are basically data
			holders and follow the JavaBean naming conventions for field access. Also you need to
			have some basic knowledge of AspectJ, especially regarding pointcuts, to use it.</para>
	</section>
	
	 <section>
	 	<title>Project and Download</title>
	 	<para>The TestDataCaptureJ project is available for download as an Eclipse project at <link xlink:href="http://github.com/davidwong/TestDataCaptureJ">Github</link>. Please see
	 		the <link xlink:href="setup.html">installation instructions</link> for the requirements.</para>
	 </section>
	
		<section>
			<title>Motivation</title>
			
			<para>The original purpose for creating this tool was to capture data to be used in unit testing
				from an enterprise web application that I was working on. The data I was
				after was the contents of a shopping basket in the checkout process.</para>
			<para>Some of ways I could have tried to do this were:</para>
			
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>to create the data manually as mock objects. However this would have required too much
						work because:</para>
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem><para>The basket items were not simple items but were more complex combinations of items. Some
								objects contained object graphs which included some fairly large
								objects (about 40 fields in one class).</para></listitem>
							<listitem><para>I needed many different items in various combinations for many test scenarios.</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>

				<listitem>
					<para>to create the data from the database. However this would have not have worked because:</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem><para>The basket items were not persistent and did not exist in the database in that form, that is they only existed in the
							user web session.</para></listitem>
						<listitem><para>A shared development database was being used by the developers on the project, and the data would be changed at
							regular intervals with a database refresh from the production system. That meant that selenium tests would go out of
							date because items that were used in the tests would no longer be available after the database refresh.</para>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>

			</itemizedlist>
			
			<para>Using the TestDataCaptureJ tool, I was able to capture the data used in the selenium tests
				and use them in JUnit tests that could be re-run without depending on the state of
				the development database.</para>
			
		</section>

	<section>
		<title>Next:</title>
		<para><link xlink:href="setup.html">Instructions on installation and setup</link></para>
		
		<para>Or you can skip ahead to other topics:<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para><link xlink:href="run.html">Instructions on running TestDataCaptureJ in an application after installation and setup has been done</link></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><link xlink:href="explanation.html">Explanation of how the test data is logged</link></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><link xlink:href="customization.html">How to customize the generated logging for unusual cases</link></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para><link xlink:href="tutorial.html">Tutorial using a Spring sample</link></para>
			</listitem>
			</itemizedlist></para>
	</section>
	
</article>
